Finding Aid for George Francis Lemble papers, 1958-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George Francis Lemble papers 1958-1968
Lemble, George Francis
2 linear feet
851711 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan businessman, president of the Washtenaw Conservatives, active in local Republican Party affairs; correspondence and other papers relating to politics, the Board of Education, the Housing Commission and Police Department of Ann Arbor, and the Willow Run project of the federal anti-poverty program.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of George F. Lemble (donor no. 4457 ) and came to the library in 1968.
The collection is open to research.
George Lemble was an insurance underwriter for the Security Mutual Life Insurance Company in Ann Arbor, Michigan. In addition, he was active in both the civic and political affairs of the city. He was an outspoken conservative, serving as president of the Washtenaw Conservatives and speaking out as a Republican in support of Barry Goldwater's candidacy in 1964 and in opposition to the creation of a housing commission and passage of a fair housing ordinance in Ann Arbor. He ran, unsuccessfully, in 1966 to the city council.
The George Lemble collection consists of a series of correspondence, clippings, newsletters and other publications dating from 1958 to 1968, and relating to his political activities in Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County. Another series of miscellaneous other papers relates to the debate over establishment of Ann Arbor Housing Commission in 1965, to his 1966 campaign for election to the Ann Arbor City Council, and to local conservative politics in general.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.). Housing Commission.; Conservatism.; Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Elections--Michigan--1964.; Elections--Michigan--1966.; Lemble, George Francis, 1924-1974.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Police--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Presidents--United States--Election--1964.; Public welfare--Michigan--Willow Run.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1961-1963.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Washtenaw County Conservatives (Mich.); Willow Run (Mich.)
Contributors:
Dearden, John F. (John Francis), 1907-1988.; Dirksen, Everett McKinley.; Durant, Richard.; Ervin, Sam J. (Sam James), 1896-1985.; Esch, Marvin Lionel, 1927-; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998.; Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Lawrence, David, 1888-; Lobsinger, Donald.; McNamara, Patrick Vincent, 1894-1966.; Meader, George, 1907-; Romney, George W., 1907-; Talmadge, Herman E. (Herman Eugene), 1913-2002.; Tower, John G. (John Goodwin), 1925-1991.; Young, Milton Ruben, 1897-1983.
- Chronological papers, undated and 1958-1968
  (correspondence, clippings, published materials, and other papers)
  - Undated and 1958-1966, 21 folders (Box 1)
  - Undated, 1966-1968, 10 folders (Box 2)
- Other papers
  - Debate over establishment of Ann Arbor Housing Commission, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Petition requesting referendum on the creation of the Ann Arbor Housing Commission, 1965 (Box 2)
  - 1966 campaign for city council, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Willow Run Association for Neighborhood Development (Box 2)
  - Business papers, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Mailing and other lists, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Clippings, flyers, and other election miscellanea, 14 folders (Box 2)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Dearden, John F. (John Francis), 1907-1988.
July 15, 1968
Dirksen, Everett McKinley.
Oct. 5, 1966
Durant, Richard
Mar. 10, 1968
Ervin, Samuel J. (Sam James), 1896-1985.
June 9, 1964
Esch, Marvin Lionel, 1927-
Mar. 22, 1967, May 9, 1967, June 18, 1968
Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998.
June 15, 1965, July 21, 1965
Griffin, Robert P. (Robert Paul), 1923-
Sept. 17, 1965, Jan. 25, 1967, Feb. 13, 1967, Mar. 16, 1967, May 4, 1967, May 16, 1967, June 6, 1967,
Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.
Apr. 14, 1964
Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), l908-1973.
Mar. 15, 1965
Lawrence, David, 1888-
Nov. 24, 1967
Lobsinger, Donald
Sept. 19, 1965
McNamara, Patrick Vincent, 1894-1966.
Apr. 14, 1964
Meader, George, 1907-
Dec. 17, 1964, Apr. 20, 1964, Apr. 28, 1964, May 1, 1964, May 20, 1964, June 24, 1964, Jan. 30, 1965
Romney, George, 1907-
Mar. 1, 1963, Oct. 15, 1963, June 26, 1964, June 21, 1965
Talmadge, Herman E. (Herman Eugene), 1913-2002.
June 1, 1964
Tower, John G. (John Goodwin), 1925-1991.
May 2, 1964
Young, Milton Reuben, 1897-1983
June 2, 1964